http://www.valottery.com/vaprivacystatement

Internet Privacy Statement
This privacy statement applies to www.valottery.com, which is owned and operated by the Virginia Lottery, and describes how we collect and use the personal information you provide us via this website. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.
Collection of personal information.
The Virginia Lottery will not collect any personal information about you (i.e., your name, address, telephone number, or email address) unless you provide it to us voluntarily. If you have access to the Internet, your computer automatically has an Internet Protocol ("IP") address. We use IP addresses to gather information to track the number of visitors to our website and to identify our most popular pages so we can improve site content.
The only ways we can obtain your personal information are if you submit it to us through one of our interactive forms or send us a general inquiry or feedback.
If you register for a Virginia Lottery subscription or promotion, create an account, or submit your information to us through our website, we may collect the following from you:
Contact information such as: name, date of birth, email address, mailing address, and phone number
Financial information such as bank account number and billing address
Last four digits of your Social Security number
Preferences information such as product wish lists, order history, and marketing preferences
If you do not want your personal information collected, please do not submit it to us! If you have already sent this information to us and would like for us to delete it, please contact us.
We use this information to:
Fulfill your subscription request
Administer your account
Confirm you are eligible to play our games or participate in our promotions
Send you requested information or respond to your questions/concerns
Send you marketing communications, such as electronic newsletters or emails
Improve our website, marketing, and business efforts
Conduct research and analysis
Display content based upon your interests
Public disclosure of your information
As part of winning prizes from the Virginia Lottery, it is our policy to reserve the right to share and display some of your information on our website and social media pages. Specific language is included in all official game and promotion rules to advise players of the specifics of this policy.
Claimants may have their first and last name, photo, hometown, and prize amount shared or displayed in these locations.
To request removal of your personal information from our website, contact us here.
In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
Sharing of your information
Except as specified above, the Virginia Lottery does not collect personal information.
We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as verifying your identity during your subscription request or fulfilling promotional prizes. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
We may also disclose your personal information:
as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process,
when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, or
to any other third party with your prior consent
Website Security
We maintain security standards and procedures regarding unauthorized access to ensure that the Virginia Lottery website remains available to all users and to prevent unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage to the site.
When you enter sensitive information on our website, that information is transmitted to the Lottery along an encrypted communication path. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
Information on individuals causing, or attempting to cause, damage to the website will be traced and released to the appropriate legal authorities to investigate suspected or actual criminal activity.
Access and choice
If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct or update it through your account settings page or by contacting us using one of the methods listed below. If you provided us with personal information but do not have an account, please contact us through the contact information listed below. We will respond to your access request within ten (10) days.
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you service. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
If you chose to receive marketing communications from us and wish to no longer receive them, you can indicate this by following the “unsubscribe” instructions provided on this site or by contacting us as indicated below.
Additional Information
Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These Features may collect your Internet protocol address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.
For your convenience the Virginia Lottery website may provide links to other sites. However, the Virginia Lottery is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of the websites to which we link. When you link to another site you are no longer on the Virginia Lottery website, and this Privacy Statement will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. If you have questions or concerns about a site to which we link, please read the privacy and security information for that site.
The Virginia Lottery does not warrant the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published on the Virginia Lottery website or any site to which we link, nor endorse any content, viewpoint, product or service linked from this system and shall not be liable for any loss caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the website. Virginia Lottery does not store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. Your friend may contact us at our Contact Us page to request that we remove this information from our database.
Contact Information
To offer comments about the Virginia Lottery website, about the information presented in this Privacy Statement, or to find your closest customer service center, please visit our Contact Us page.
Our headquarters is located at, and our mailing address is, 600 E. Main Street, Richmond, VA 23219.
Information collected and how it is used
If you do nothing during your visit to the Virginia Lottery website but browse or download information, we automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:
The Internet Domain and IP address from which you accessed our site.
The type of browser and operating system you used.
The date and time you visited our site.
The pages visited. If you linked from another website, the address of that website.
The information collected is used to improve the content of our web services and help us understand how people are using our pages. We analyze our website logs to continually improve the value of the content available on our site. The information in our web logs is not personally viewable and no attempt is made to link it with individuals who browse our website.
If during your visit to the Virginia Lottery website you send an email message, we collect your email address and the contents of the message you sent us. We use your email address to respond to you.
Cookies
Cookies and Technologies used by the Virginia Lottery
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies on this website.
Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate our site while persistent cookies enable us to track the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.
Session cookies expire when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.
You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site may be limited.
As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.
This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.
We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.
Technologies used by Third Parties
We and our third party partners use technologies such as cookies, web beacons, tags and scripts to help us understand how users interact with our site, assist with managing our website and assist with our advertising efforts. Web beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, web beacons are embedded invisibly on web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence
Our advertising partner uses cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you with advertising based upon your interests.
If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you specific ads, you may opt-out by clicking here or here.
Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.
You will continue to receive generic ads.
The information collected by these technologies is not tied to any personal information you may have submitted to us.
We use Local Shared Objects, such as Flash cookies to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. To manage Flash cookies, please click here.
Effective September 29, 2017
Lottery Services Portal Privacy Statement
Thank you for visiting the Lottery Services Portal, a website portal ("Portal") operated on behalf of the Virginia Lottery (herein “VAL,” "we" or "us") by VAL’s gaming system provider. This Portal is intended and authorized for use and access by official licensed VAL Retailers ("Retailer") only. This Privacy Policy ("Policy") explains the online information practices of the VAL and sets out what information we collect through the Portal, how we collect it, and what we do with it. Please contact us as indicated in the "Contact Us" section below if you have any questions or would like additional information. We may update this Policy from time to time, so please check this Policy periodically for changes.
Your Information
We may collect non-public, personal information when you use this Portal or when you communicate and/or interact with us through this Portal. Pursuant to Virginia Code §§ 2.2-3800, et seq., “personal information” means all information that (i) describes, locates or indexes anything about an individual including, but not limited to, his social security number, driver's license number, agency-issued identification number, student identification number, real or personal property holdings derived from tax returns, and his education, financial transactions, medical history, ancestry, religion, political ideology, criminal or employment record, or (ii) affords a basis for inferring personal characteristics, such as finger and voice prints, photographs, or things done by or to such individual; and the record of his presence, registration, or membership in an organization or activity, or admission to an institution. "Personal information" shall not include routine information maintained for the purpose of internal office administration whose use could not be such as to affect adversely any data subject nor does the term include real estate assessment information. Personal information does not include any public information about an individual that is available through federal, state or local public records or business information collected through the Portal. We will update your information as information is processed through the Portal and/or new information is made available to us in an effort to keep your information current, accurate and complete or inform you if we are unable to process any requested update and the reason. Only authorized Retailers who provide us with the requested information will be able to access and obtain Retailer reports, data and other information relevant to Retailer's account and status as a Retailer available by or through the Portal (as determined by us in our discretion), and/or otherwise participate in the Portal's activities and offerings ("Retailer Information"). Portal usage, measurement, analytics and other data and information available to us directly or from our service providers in aggregated or other non-personalized forms or formats are outside the scope of this Privacy Policy and not subject to the collection or usage restrictions set forth herein.
Our Use of Your Information
If we do receive your personal information through the Portal, we will only use it for the purposes described where it is collected or otherwise as described in this Policy. Specifically, we reserve all rights necessary to use and disclose your personal information as required and/or permitted pursuant to all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the VAL. We may use information submitted through the Portal to communicate with you about matters related to your status as a Retailer, your use of the features and services available through the Portal and additional products and services that may be of interest to you. We may combine information we collect about you through the Portal with information we obtain about you from other sources, including aggregate data from third parties. We will not sell, license, transmit or disclose this information outside of our organization unless (1) you expressly authorize us to do so; (2) it is necessary to allow our service providers or agents to provide Retailer Information for us or on our behalf, (3) it is necessary to allow our vendors to provide you third-party products and services owned or controlled by them through this Portal, to provide services for the Portal for us or on our behalf, including processing, hosting and customer surveys, and to provide services and other products for vendor on vendor's behalf subject to additional terms and policies, (4) it is necessary in order to provide our Retailer Information to you, including in connection with the review, processing and consideration of any application for Retailer Information submitted by you, including verification, authentication, geolocation and authorization for any requests (and contacting you when necessary), (5) subject to applicable contractual or legal restrictions, it is disclosed to entities that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other entities with whom we have joint marketing agreements, (6) it is necessary in connection with other business purposes including, without limitation, operation and administration of this Portal and/or Retailer Information offered through the Portal, customer care or convenience, service quality, business management and operation, risk assessment, security, fraud and crime prevention/detection, monitoring, research and analysis, marketing, customer purchasing preferences and trends, dispute resolution, credit checking and debt collection, account maintenance and fulfillment activities, and awarding and payment of prizes, as applicable, including tax reporting and performance of other compliance and offset obligations required or permitted by law in connection therewith, (7) otherwise as we are required or permitted by law. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, as required by the Virginia Freedom of Information Act and the Virginia state lottery laws, certain information collected through our Portal or provided by you to us through our Portal will be regarded as matters of public record and may be released by us to the public.
If you do not agree to Our Use of Your Information above, we cannot do business with you or accept requests for Retailer Information from you through the Portal. Your continued use of this Portal and request for any Retailer Information available through the Portal constitutes your acceptance of this Policy. By interacting through the Portal, you agree and consent to conduct the transactions available through the Portal and to communicate with us regarding all such matters by electronic means.
Comments and Feedback
We appreciate your questions, comments and feedback ("Feedback") about us, the Portal and the Retailer Information available through the Portal and welcome your messages. We will share your Feedback with those within our organization and to applicable third-party providers who we believe are most capable of addressing your questions and comments. We may archive your Feedback for a certain period of time or discard it in accordance with the Commonwealth of Virginia records retention schedules applicable to the VAL.
Your Rights
Subject to applicable terms and conditions, we may allow you to use the Portal for a reasonable period of time (as determined by us in our discretion) following your termination as a Retailer. Thereafter, we will only retain copies of your information as necessary for us to comply with governmental orders, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, and enforce any agreement you have entered into with us and as otherwise reasonably necessary for our business purposes, including compliance with all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the VAL, the Portal and the Retailer Information. The foregoing does not constitute, and we do not make any representation, express, implied or statutory, all of which are hereby expressly disclaimed, that all electronic copies of your information will be destroyed. For clarity, with respect to certain Retailer Information available through the Portal, our ability to remove or stop using information submitted from you that is fundamental to your ability to receive or continue to receive and/or benefit from the Retailer Information and Portal is limited by all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the VAL and that specific Product.
Use of Tools, "Cookies" and Links to Other Websites
This Portal may use "cookies". Cookies allow us to identify your computer, but not you personally. You can set your web browser to refuse cookies. However, if you do so, you may not be able to enjoy access and use all of the Retailer Information and services available to you on this Portal.
We and our third-party service providers and partners may collect information relating to analytics, customer trends and patterns and use cookies and software tools to measure Portal usage and related information. If you are requesting Retailer Information and/or submitting Feedback to us through the Portal, we may also use cookies to keep track of the request from one web page to another. We retain both the cookie information and/or the information you provide to us online to complete a request for Retailer Information by you or to keep historical records of your past requests. In other cases, we may retain the cookie and/or online information you give us for your use in subsequent sessions and requests.
An Internet Protocol ("IP") address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you visit this Portal, we may view the IP address (which may include the city, domain address and service provider) of the device you use to connect to the Internet. We use this information to determine the general physical location of the device, understand the general location of visitors to this Portal and verify eligibility to participate in certain features and offerings of the Portal. We also may use this information to enhance this Portal.
Certain pages on our Portal contain "web beacons" (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). These web beacons allow us and our third-party service providers and partners to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in cookies set by the third party.
For third-party products and services available to you through this Portal, we may share any or all of the information we collect with such provider to assist in your receipt of and access to such products and services. In such circumstances, you may be asked to accept the terms and policies of such provider. You should read all applicable terms and policies carefully to ensure you understand how such third-party may use your information.
Monitoring
To ensure that we carry out your instructions accurately, improve our Portal, Retailer Information and services, provide security and enable compliance with all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the VAL and its Portal and Retailer Information, we may monitor and/or record: (1) telephone calls; and (2) interactions, transactions and activities on this Portal. All recordings and other records are our sole property. Your access to the Portal constitutes your consent and agreement to such monitoring. The results of such monitoring may be used in civil or criminal actions as deemed appropriate or necessary by us.
Security Statement
We take reasonable steps to protect your personal information, including keeping your personal information private and safe. You acknowledge, however, that no transmission of data over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, despite our efforts. Thus, while we will use and will require our applicable service providers to use reasonable means consistent with general industry standards to secure information you transmit to us consistent with our legal requirements, we cannot guarantee that such information will not be intercepted by third parties.
Visiting This Portal From Outside Of the United States
If you are visiting this Portal or attempting to access Retailer Information from outside of the United States or otherwise contacting us from outside of the United States, please be aware that your personal information may be transferred to, stored or processed in the United States, where many of the service providers and servers related to this Portal are located. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, but please be assured that we take steps to protect your privacy. Nothing in this Section is intended to expand or otherwise alter any provisions set forth or referenced in the Portal Terms of Use limiting access to and use of the Portal and Retailer Information available on or through the Portal to certain locations.
Changes to this Policy
We may change this Policy at any time. Any changes to this Policy will be posted on this Portal or made available on request. The most recent version of the Policy is reflected by the version date located at the bottom of this Policy. This Policy is not intended to and does not create any contractual or other legal right in or on behalf of any party.
Links to Other Websites
For your convenience, we may provide links to other websites and web pages that we do not control. We cannot be responsible for the terms of use or privacy practices of any websites, pages, products or services not under our control and we do not endorse any of these websites or pages, the services or products described or offered on such websites or pages, or any of the content contained on those websites or pages, and expressly disclaim any liability associated with your access or use of the same. Please refer to the privacy policies applicable to those third-party websites.
How to Contact Us
If you have any questions about this Policy or would like to learn more about how we protect privacy, please contact us by any of the channels described in “Contact Us” section of the Portal.
Effective March 21, 2019
Virginia Lottery Mobile Application Privacy Statement
Privacy Statement
This privacy statement applies to the Virginia Lottery mobile application (“Mobile App”), which is owned and operated by the Virginia Lottery, and describes how we collect and use the personal information you provide us via the application. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.
COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
The Virginia Lottery will not collect any personal information about you (i.e., your name, address, telephone number, or email address) unless you provide it to us voluntarily. If you have access to the Internet, your device automatically has an Internet Protocol ("IP") address. We use IP addresses to gather information to track the number of users of our application and to identify our most popular screens so we can improve application content.
We can obtain your personal information only when you submit it to us through one of our interactive forms or send us a general inquiry or feedback.
If you submit your information to us through our application, we may collect the following from you:
contact information you voluntarily provide, such as: name, date of birth, email address, mailing address, and phone number, and/or
preferences information such as product wish lists, order history, favorites, saved playslips, promotional announcements, and/or marketing preferences
If you do not want your personal information collected, please do not submit it to us! If you have already sent this information to us and would like for us to delete it, please contact us.
We use this information to:
Send you requested information or respond to your questions/concerns
Send you marketing communications, such as electronic newsletters, emails, and/or push notifications
Send you notifications relating to your selected preferences, such as winning numbers
Improve our website, marketing, and business efforts
Conduct research and analysis
To request removal of your personal information from our database, contact us here.  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know that we are unable to do so and why.
SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION
Except as specified above, the Virginia Lottery does not collect personal information.
We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as fulfilling promotional prizes and/or to resolve a technical issue you have reported to us. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
We may disclose your personal information:
as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process;
when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request; or
to any other third party with your prior consent.
APPLICATION SECURITY
We maintain security standards and procedures regarding unauthorized access to ensure that the Virginia Lottery application remains available to all users and to prevent unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage to the application.
Information on individuals causing, or attempting to cause, damage to the application will be traced and released to the appropriate legal authorities to investigate suspected or actual criminal activity.
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION
For your convenience the Virginia Lottery mobile application may provide links to other sites. However, the Virginia Lottery is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of the websites to which we link. When you link to another site you are no longer on the Virginia Lottery mobile application, and this Privacy Statement will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. If you have questions or concerns about a site to which we link, please read the privacy and security information for that site.
The Virginia Lottery does not warrant the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published on the Virginia Lottery mobile application or any site to which we link, nor endorse any content, viewpoint, product or service linked from this system and shall not be liable for any loss caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on this application prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy for the latest information on our privacy practices.
CONTACT INFORMATION
To offer comments about the Virginia Lottery mobile application , about the information presented in this Privacy Policy, or to find your closest customer service center, please visit our Contact Us page.  Our headquarters is located at, and our mailing address is, 600 E. Main Street, Richmond, VA 23219.
INFORMATION COLLECTED AND HOW IT IS USED
If you do nothing with the Virginia Lottery mobile application but browse or download information, we automatically collect and store information about your usage of the app that may include, but is not limited to:
the Internet Domain and IP address, including geographical location, from which you accessed our site;
the mobile device identifier and hardware;
your network carrier;
the type of browser and operating system you used;
the date and time you accessed our application and items you clicked on;
the screens visited and images requested;
whether you linked from another website or application and the address of that website/application; and
searches you initiated.
The information collected is used to improve the content of our application services and help us understand how people are using our application in order to make it more useful and accessible to users. We analyze our application logs to continually improve the value of the available content. The information in our logs is not personally identifiable and no attempt is made to link it with individuals who download our application.
If, during your visit to the Virginia Lottery application, you send an email message, we collect your email address and the contents of the message you sent us. We use your email address to respond to you.
Cookies and Technologies used by the Virginia Lottery
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s device for record-keeping purposes. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies on this application.  Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate our application while persistent cookies enable us to track the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.  Session cookies expire when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.
You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. If you reject cookies, you may still use our application, but your ability to use some of its features may be limited.
As is true of most applications, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.
We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the application, to track how the application is used and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.
Technologies used by Third Parties
We and our third-party partners use technologies such as cookies, web beacons, tags and scripts to help us understand how users interact with our application and assist with managing our application. Web beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, used to track the online movements of application users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s device hard drive, web beacons are embedded invisibly on application pages and are approximately the size of the period at the end of this sentence.
The information collected by these technologies is not tied to any personal information you may have submitted to us.
Effective July 21, 2020
Vendor Portal Privacy Statement
Privacy Statement
This privacy statement applies to the Lottery Vendor Portal, which is owned and operated by the Virginia Lottery, and describes how we collect and use the personal information you provide us via this website. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.
Personal Information
Collection
The Virginia Lottery will not collect any personal information about you (i.e., your name, address, telephone number, or email address) unless you provide it to us voluntarily. If you have access to the Internet, your computer automatically has an Internet Protocol ("IP") address. We use IP addresses to gather information to track the number of visitors to our website and to identify our most popular pages so we can improve site content.
The only ways we can obtain your personal information are if you submit it to us through one of our interactive forms or send us a general inquiry or feedback.
If you register for an account through the Virginia Lottery Vendor Portal, or submit your information to us through our website, we may collect contact information from you including, but not limited to, your name, date of birth, email address, business mailing address, and phone number.
Use
We use this information to:
administer your account;
communicate potential business opportunities, open solicitations, etc.; and/or
send you requested information or respond to your questions/concerns.
If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, please correct or update it through the Profile page on the Vendor Portal.
Retention
To request removal of your personal information from our website, please contact us via email at vendorservices@valottery.com. We will not be able to remove any information that is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Sharing/Selling
Except as specified herein, the Virginia Lottery does not share or sell your personal information to third parties unless:
required by law, such as to comply with a request under the Virginia Freedom of Information Act or a subpoena or similar legal process, and/or
we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, and/or
you have given us your prior consent to do so.
Access And Choice
Vendors have the option of selecting procurement categories (commodity codes) for which they are able to provide goods and services.
Vendors will receive emails notifying them of solicitation releases and associated addendums for any solicitation which matches the associated procurement categories the vendor has chosen.
Website Security
We maintain security standards and procedures regarding unauthorized access to ensure that the Virginia Lottery Vendor Portal remains available to all users and to prevent unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage to the site.
When you enter sensitive information on our website, that information is transmitted to the Lottery along an encrypted communication path. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
Information on individuals causing, or attempting to cause, damage to the website will be traced and released to the appropriate legal authorities to investigate suspected or actual criminal activity.
Additional Information
The Lottery Vendor Portal utilizes Centrify to authenticate Vendor Portal users.
Centrify utilizes Facebook, LinkedIn, Google, and Microsoft account information to provide log-in capabilities for the Vendor Portal.
The Lottery is not responsible for the security or maintenance of the user names and passwords for these sites. Click here to view Centrify’s privacy policy.
For your convenience the Virginia Lottery website may provide links to other sites, including our own. However, the Virginia Lottery is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any websites to which we link that are not ours. When you click a link to visit another site, you are no longer on the Virginia Lottery Vendor Portal, and this Privacy Statement will no longer apply. At that point, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. If you have questions or concerns about a site to which we link, please read the privacy and security information for that site.
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
Cookies
Cookies and Technologies used by the Virginia Lottery
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies on this website.
Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate our site while persistent cookies enable us to track the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.
Session cookies expire when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.
You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site may be limited.
As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.
This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.
Contact Information
To offer comments about the Virginia Lottery Vendor Portal or to ask about the information presented in this Privacy Statement, please email us at vendorservices@valottery.com.
Our headquarters location and mailing address is: 600 E. Main Street, Richmond, VA 23219.
Effective February 7, 2019
Internet
Internet Privacy Statement
This privacy statement applies to www.valottery.com, which is owned and operated by the Virginia Lottery, and describes how we collect and use the personal information you provide us via this website. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.
Collection of personal information.
The Virginia Lottery will not collect any personal information about you (i.e., your name, address, telephone number, or email address) unless you provide it to us voluntarily. If you have access to the Internet, your computer automatically has an Internet Protocol ("IP") address. We use IP addresses to gather information to track the number of visitors to our website and to identify our most popular pages so we can improve site content.
The only ways we can obtain your personal information are if you submit it to us through one of our interactive forms or send us a general inquiry or feedback.
If you register for a Virginia Lottery subscription or promotion, create an account, or submit your information to us through our website, we may collect the following from you:
Contact information such as: name, date of birth, email address, mailing address, and phone number
Financial information such as bank account number and billing address
Last four digits of your Social Security number
Preferences information such as product wish lists, order history, and marketing preferences
If you do not want your personal information collected, please do not submit it to us! If you have already sent this information to us and would like for us to delete it, please contact us.
We use this information to:
Fulfill your subscription request
Administer your account
Confirm you are eligible to play our games or participate in our promotions
Send you requested information or respond to your questions/concerns
Send you marketing communications, such as electronic newsletters or emails
Improve our website, marketing, and business efforts
Conduct research and analysis
Display content based upon your interests
Public disclosure of your information
As part of winning prizes from the Virginia Lottery, it is our policy to reserve the right to share and display some of your information on our website and social media pages. Specific language is included in all official game and promotion rules to advise players of the specifics of this policy.
Claimants may have their first and last name, photo, hometown, and prize amount shared or displayed in these locations.
To request removal of your personal information from our website, contact us here.
In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
Sharing of your information
Except as specified above, the Virginia Lottery does not collect personal information.
We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as verifying your identity during your subscription request or fulfilling promotional prizes. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
We may also disclose your personal information:
as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process,
when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, or
to any other third party with your prior consent
Website Security
We maintain security standards and procedures regarding unauthorized access to ensure that the Virginia Lottery website remains available to all users and to prevent unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage to the site.
When you enter sensitive information on our website, that information is transmitted to the Lottery along an encrypted communication path. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
Information on individuals causing, or attempting to cause, damage to the website will be traced and released to the appropriate legal authorities to investigate suspected or actual criminal activity.
Access and choice
If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct or update it through your account settings page or by contacting us using one of the methods listed below. If you provided us with personal information but do not have an account, please contact us through the contact information listed below. We will respond to your access request within ten (10) days.
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you service. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
If you chose to receive marketing communications from us and wish to no longer receive them, you can indicate this by following the “unsubscribe” instructions provided on this site or by contacting us as indicated below.
Additional Information
Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These Features may collect your Internet protocol address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.
For your convenience the Virginia Lottery website may provide links to other sites. However, the Virginia Lottery is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of the websites to which we link. When you link to another site you are no longer on the Virginia Lottery website, and this Privacy Statement will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. If you have questions or concerns about a site to which we link, please read the privacy and security information for that site.
The Virginia Lottery does not warrant the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published on the Virginia Lottery website or any site to which we link, nor endorse any content, viewpoint, product or service linked from this system and shall not be liable for any loss caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the website. Virginia Lottery does not store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. Your friend may contact us at our Contact Us page to request that we remove this information from our database.
Contact Information
To offer comments about the Virginia Lottery website, about the information presented in this Privacy Statement, or to find your closest customer service center, please visit our Contact Us page.
Our headquarters is located at, and our mailing address is, 600 E. Main Street, Richmond, VA 23219.
Information collected and how it is used
If you do nothing during your visit to the Virginia Lottery website but browse or download information, we automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:
The Internet Domain and IP address from which you accessed our site.
The type of browser and operating system you used.
The date and time you visited our site.
The pages visited. If you linked from another website, the address of that website.
The information collected is used to improve the content of our web services and help us understand how people are using our pages. We analyze our website logs to continually improve the value of the content available on our site. The information in our web logs is not personally viewable and no attempt is made to link it with individuals who browse our website.
If during your visit to the Virginia Lottery website you send an email message, we collect your email address and the contents of the message you sent us. We use your email address to respond to you.
Cookies
Cookies and Technologies used by the Virginia Lottery
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies on this website.
Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate our site while persistent cookies enable us to track the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.
Session cookies expire when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.
You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site may be limited.
As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.
This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.
We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.
Technologies used by Third Parties
We and our third party partners use technologies such as cookies, web beacons, tags and scripts to help us understand how users interact with our site, assist with managing our website and assist with our advertising efforts. Web beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, web beacons are embedded invisibly on web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence
Our advertising partner uses cookies and web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you with advertising based upon your interests.
If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you specific ads, you may opt-out by clicking here or here.
Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.
You will continue to receive generic ads.
The information collected by these technologies is not tied to any personal information you may have submitted to us.
We use Local Shared Objects, such as Flash cookies to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. To manage Flash cookies, please click here.
Effective September 29, 2017
Lottery Services Portal
Lottery Services Portal Privacy Statement
Thank you for visiting the Lottery Services Portal, a website portal ("Portal") operated on behalf of the Virginia Lottery (herein “VAL,” "we" or "us") by VAL’s gaming system provider. This Portal is intended and authorized for use and access by official licensed VAL Retailers ("Retailer") only. This Privacy Policy ("Policy") explains the online information practices of the VAL and sets out what information we collect through the Portal, how we collect it, and what we do with it. Please contact us as indicated in the "Contact Us" section below if you have any questions or would like additional information. We may update this Policy from time to time, so please check this Policy periodically for changes.
Your Information
We may collect non-public, personal information when you use this Portal or when you communicate and/or interact with us through this Portal. Pursuant to Virginia Code §§ 2.2-3800, et seq., “personal information” means all information that (i) describes, locates or indexes anything about an individual including, but not limited to, his social security number, driver's license number, agency-issued identification number, student identification number, real or personal property holdings derived from tax returns, and his education, financial transactions, medical history, ancestry, religion, political ideology, criminal or employment record, or (ii) affords a basis for inferring personal characteristics, such as finger and voice prints, photographs, or things done by or to such individual; and the record of his presence, registration, or membership in an organization or activity, or admission to an institution. "Personal information" shall not include routine information maintained for the purpose of internal office administration whose use could not be such as to affect adversely any data subject nor does the term include real estate assessment information. Personal information does not include any public information about an individual that is available through federal, state or local public records or business information collected through the Portal. We will update your information as information is processed through the Portal and/or new information is made available to us in an effort to keep your information current, accurate and complete or inform you if we are unable to process any requested update and the reason. Only authorized Retailers who provide us with the requested information will be able to access and obtain Retailer reports, data and other information relevant to Retailer's account and status as a Retailer available by or through the Portal (as determined by us in our discretion), and/or otherwise participate in the Portal's activities and offerings ("Retailer Information"). Portal usage, measurement, analytics and other data and information available to us directly or from our service providers in aggregated or other non-personalized forms or formats are outside the scope of this Privacy Policy and not subject to the collection or usage restrictions set forth herein.
Our Use of Your Information
If we do receive your personal information through the Portal, we will only use it for the purposes described where it is collected or otherwise as described in this Policy. Specifically, we reserve all rights necessary to use and disclose your personal information as required and/or permitted pursuant to all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the VAL. We may use information submitted through the Portal to communicate with you about matters related to your status as a Retailer, your use of the features and services available through the Portal and additional products and services that may be of interest to you. We may combine information we collect about you through the Portal with information we obtain about you from other sources, including aggregate data from third parties. We will not sell, license, transmit or disclose this information outside of our organization unless (1) you expressly authorize us to do so; (2) it is necessary to allow our service providers or agents to provide Retailer Information for us or on our behalf, (3) it is necessary to allow our vendors to provide you third-party products and services owned or controlled by them through this Portal, to provide services for the Portal for us or on our behalf, including processing, hosting and customer surveys, and to provide services and other products for vendor on vendor's behalf subject to additional terms and policies, (4) it is necessary in order to provide our Retailer Information to you, including in connection with the review, processing and consideration of any application for Retailer Information submitted by you, including verification, authentication, geolocation and authorization for any requests (and contacting you when necessary), (5) subject to applicable contractual or legal restrictions, it is disclosed to entities that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other entities with whom we have joint marketing agreements, (6) it is necessary in connection with other business purposes including, without limitation, operation and administration of this Portal and/or Retailer Information offered through the Portal, customer care or convenience, service quality, business management and operation, risk assessment, security, fraud and crime prevention/detection, monitoring, research and analysis, marketing, customer purchasing preferences and trends, dispute resolution, credit checking and debt collection, account maintenance and fulfillment activities, and awarding and payment of prizes, as applicable, including tax reporting and performance of other compliance and offset obligations required or permitted by law in connection therewith, (7) otherwise as we are required or permitted by law. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, as required by the Virginia Freedom of Information Act and the Virginia state lottery laws, certain information collected through our Portal or provided by you to us through our Portal will be regarded as matters of public record and may be released by us to the public.
If you do not agree to Our Use of Your Information above, we cannot do business with you or accept requests for Retailer Information from you through the Portal. Your continued use of this Portal and request for any Retailer Information available through the Portal constitutes your acceptance of this Policy. By interacting through the Portal, you agree and consent to conduct the transactions available through the Portal and to communicate with us regarding all such matters by electronic means.
Comments and Feedback
We appreciate your questions, comments and feedback ("Feedback") about us, the Portal and the Retailer Information available through the Portal and welcome your messages. We will share your Feedback with those within our organization and to applicable third-party providers who we believe are most capable of addressing your questions and comments. We may archive your Feedback for a certain period of time or discard it in accordance with the Commonwealth of Virginia records retention schedules applicable to the VAL.
Your Rights
Subject to applicable terms and conditions, we may allow you to use the Portal for a reasonable period of time (as determined by us in our discretion) following your termination as a Retailer. Thereafter, we will only retain copies of your information as necessary for us to comply with governmental orders, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, and enforce any agreement you have entered into with us and as otherwise reasonably necessary for our business purposes, including compliance with all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the VAL, the Portal and the Retailer Information. The foregoing does not constitute, and we do not make any representation, express, implied or statutory, all of which are hereby expressly disclaimed, that all electronic copies of your information will be destroyed. For clarity, with respect to certain Retailer Information available through the Portal, our ability to remove or stop using information submitted from you that is fundamental to your ability to receive or continue to receive and/or benefit from the Retailer Information and Portal is limited by all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the VAL and that specific Product.
Use of Tools, "Cookies" and Links to Other Websites
This Portal may use "cookies". Cookies allow us to identify your computer, but not you personally. You can set your web browser to refuse cookies. However, if you do so, you may not be able to enjoy access and use all of the Retailer Information and services available to you on this Portal.
We and our third-party service providers and partners may collect information relating to analytics, customer trends and patterns and use cookies and software tools to measure Portal usage and related information. If you are requesting Retailer Information and/or submitting Feedback to us through the Portal, we may also use cookies to keep track of the request from one web page to another. We retain both the cookie information and/or the information you provide to us online to complete a request for Retailer Information by you or to keep historical records of your past requests. In other cases, we may retain the cookie and/or online information you give us for your use in subsequent sessions and requests.
An Internet Protocol ("IP") address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you visit this Portal, we may view the IP address (which may include the city, domain address and service provider) of the device you use to connect to the Internet. We use this information to determine the general physical location of the device, understand the general location of visitors to this Portal and verify eligibility to participate in certain features and offerings of the Portal. We also may use this information to enhance this Portal.
Certain pages on our Portal contain "web beacons" (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). These web beacons allow us and our third-party service providers and partners to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in cookies set by the third party.
For third-party products and services available to you through this Portal, we may share any or all of the information we collect with such provider to assist in your receipt of and access to such products and services. In such circumstances, you may be asked to accept the terms and policies of such provider. You should read all applicable terms and policies carefully to ensure you understand how such third-party may use your information.
Monitoring
To ensure that we carry out your instructions accurately, improve our Portal, Retailer Information and services, provide security and enable compliance with all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the VAL and its Portal and Retailer Information, we may monitor and/or record: (1) telephone calls; and (2) interactions, transactions and activities on this Portal. All recordings and other records are our sole property. Your access to the Portal constitutes your consent and agreement to such monitoring. The results of such monitoring may be used in civil or criminal actions as deemed appropriate or necessary by us.
Security Statement
We take reasonable steps to protect your personal information, including keeping your personal information private and safe. You acknowledge, however, that no transmission of data over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, despite our efforts. Thus, while we will use and will require our applicable service providers to use reasonable means consistent with general industry standards to secure information you transmit to us consistent with our legal requirements, we cannot guarantee that such information will not be intercepted by third parties.
Visiting This Portal From Outside Of the United States
If you are visiting this Portal or attempting to access Retailer Information from outside of the United States or otherwise contacting us from outside of the United States, please be aware that your personal information may be transferred to, stored or processed in the United States, where many of the service providers and servers related to this Portal are located. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, but please be assured that we take steps to protect your privacy. Nothing in this Section is intended to expand or otherwise alter any provisions set forth or referenced in the Portal Terms of Use limiting access to and use of the Portal and Retailer Information available on or through the Portal to certain locations.
Changes to this Policy
We may change this Policy at any time. Any changes to this Policy will be posted on this Portal or made available on request. The most recent version of the Policy is reflected by the version date located at the bottom of this Policy. This Policy is not intended to and does not create any contractual or other legal right in or on behalf of any party.
Links to Other Websites
For your convenience, we may provide links to other websites and web pages that we do not control. We cannot be responsible for the terms of use or privacy practices of any websites, pages, products or services not under our control and we do not endorse any of these websites or pages, the services or products described or offered on such websites or pages, or any of the content contained on those websites or pages, and expressly disclaim any liability associated with your access or use of the same. Please refer to the privacy policies applicable to those third-party websites.
How to Contact Us
If you have any questions about this Policy or would like to learn more about how we protect privacy, please contact us by any of the channels described in “Contact Us” section of the Portal.
Effective March 21, 2019
Mobile Application
Virginia Lottery Mobile Application Privacy Statement
Privacy Statement
This privacy statement applies to the Virginia Lottery mobile application (“Mobile App”), which is owned and operated by the Virginia Lottery, and describes how we collect and use the personal information you provide us via the application. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.
COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
The Virginia Lottery will not collect any personal information about you (i.e., your name, address, telephone number, or email address) unless you provide it to us voluntarily. If you have access to the Internet, your device automatically has an Internet Protocol ("IP") address. We use IP addresses to gather information to track the number of users of our application and to identify our most popular screens so we can improve application content.
We can obtain your personal information only when you submit it to us through one of our interactive forms or send us a general inquiry or feedback.
If you submit your information to us through our application, we may collect the following from you:
contact information you voluntarily provide, such as: name, date of birth, email address, mailing address, and phone number, and/or
preferences information such as product wish lists, order history, favorites, saved playslips, promotional announcements, and/or marketing preferences
If you do not want your personal information collected, please do not submit it to us! If you have already sent this information to us and would like for us to delete it, please contact us.
We use this information to:
Send you requested information or respond to your questions/concerns
Send you marketing communications, such as electronic newsletters, emails, and/or push notifications
Send you notifications relating to your selected preferences, such as winning numbers
Improve our website, marketing, and business efforts
Conduct research and analysis
To request removal of your personal information from our database, contact us here.  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know that we are unable to do so and why.
SHARING OF YOUR INFORMATION
Except as specified above, the Virginia Lottery does not collect personal information.
We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as fulfilling promotional prizes and/or to resolve a technical issue you have reported to us. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
We may disclose your personal information:
as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process;
when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request; or
to any other third party with your prior consent.
APPLICATION SECURITY
We maintain security standards and procedures regarding unauthorized access to ensure that the Virginia Lottery application remains available to all users and to prevent unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage to the application.
Information on individuals causing, or attempting to cause, damage to the application will be traced and released to the appropriate legal authorities to investigate suspected or actual criminal activity.
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION
For your convenience the Virginia Lottery mobile application may provide links to other sites. However, the Virginia Lottery is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of the websites to which we link. When you link to another site you are no longer on the Virginia Lottery mobile application, and this Privacy Statement will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. If you have questions or concerns about a site to which we link, please read the privacy and security information for that site.
The Virginia Lottery does not warrant the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published on the Virginia Lottery mobile application or any site to which we link, nor endorse any content, viewpoint, product or service linked from this system and shall not be liable for any loss caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by means of a notice on this application prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy for the latest information on our privacy practices.
CONTACT INFORMATION
To offer comments about the Virginia Lottery mobile application , about the information presented in this Privacy Policy, or to find your closest customer service center, please visit our Contact Us page.  Our headquarters is located at, and our mailing address is, 600 E. Main Street, Richmond, VA 23219.
INFORMATION COLLECTED AND HOW IT IS USED
If you do nothing with the Virginia Lottery mobile application but browse or download information, we automatically collect and store information about your usage of the app that may include, but is not limited to:
the Internet Domain and IP address, including geographical location, from which you accessed our site;
the mobile device identifier and hardware;
your network carrier;
the type of browser and operating system you used;
the date and time you accessed our application and items you clicked on;
the screens visited and images requested;
whether you linked from another website or application and the address of that website/application; and
searches you initiated.
The information collected is used to improve the content of our application services and help us understand how people are using our application in order to make it more useful and accessible to users. We analyze our application logs to continually improve the value of the available content. The information in our logs is not personally identifiable and no attempt is made to link it with individuals who download our application.
If, during your visit to the Virginia Lottery application, you send an email message, we collect your email address and the contents of the message you sent us. We use your email address to respond to you.
Cookies and Technologies used by the Virginia Lottery
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s device for record-keeping purposes. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies on this application.  Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate our application while persistent cookies enable us to track the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.  Session cookies expire when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.
You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. If you reject cookies, you may still use our application, but your ability to use some of its features may be limited.
As is true of most applications, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.
We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the application, to track how the application is used and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.
Technologies used by Third Parties
We and our third-party partners use technologies such as cookies, web beacons, tags and scripts to help us understand how users interact with our application and assist with managing our application. Web beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, used to track the online movements of application users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s device hard drive, web beacons are embedded invisibly on application pages and are approximately the size of the period at the end of this sentence.
The information collected by these technologies is not tied to any personal information you may have submitted to us.
Effective July 21, 2020
Vendor Portal
Vendor Portal Privacy Statement
Privacy Statement
This privacy statement applies to the Lottery Vendor Portal, which is owned and operated by the Virginia Lottery, and describes how we collect and use the personal information you provide us via this website. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.
Personal Information
Collection
The Virginia Lottery will not collect any personal information about you (i.e., your name, address, telephone number, or email address) unless you provide it to us voluntarily. If you have access to the Internet, your computer automatically has an Internet Protocol ("IP") address. We use IP addresses to gather information to track the number of visitors to our website and to identify our most popular pages so we can improve site content.
The only ways we can obtain your personal information are if you submit it to us through one of our interactive forms or send us a general inquiry or feedback.
If you register for an account through the Virginia Lottery Vendor Portal, or submit your information to us through our website, we may collect contact information from you including, but not limited to, your name, date of birth, email address, business mailing address, and phone number.
Use
We use this information to:
administer your account;
communicate potential business opportunities, open solicitations, etc.; and/or
send you requested information or respond to your questions/concerns.
If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, please correct or update it through the Profile page on the Vendor Portal.
Retention
To request removal of your personal information from our website, please contact us via email at vendorservices@valottery.com. We will not be able to remove any information that is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Sharing/Selling
Except as specified herein, the Virginia Lottery does not share or sell your personal information to third parties unless:
required by law, such as to comply with a request under the Virginia Freedom of Information Act or a subpoena or similar legal process, and/or
we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, and/or
you have given us your prior consent to do so.
Access And Choice
Vendors have the option of selecting procurement categories (commodity codes) for which they are able to provide goods and services.
Vendors will receive emails notifying them of solicitation releases and associated addendums for any solicitation which matches the associated procurement categories the vendor has chosen.
Website Security
We maintain security standards and procedures regarding unauthorized access to ensure that the Virginia Lottery Vendor Portal remains available to all users and to prevent unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage to the site.
When you enter sensitive information on our website, that information is transmitted to the Lottery along an encrypted communication path. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
Information on individuals causing, or attempting to cause, damage to the website will be traced and released to the appropriate legal authorities to investigate suspected or actual criminal activity.
Additional Information
The Lottery Vendor Portal utilizes Centrify to authenticate Vendor Portal users.
Centrify utilizes Facebook, LinkedIn, Google, and Microsoft account information to provide log-in capabilities for the Vendor Portal.
The Lottery is not responsible for the security or maintenance of the user names and passwords for these sites. Click here to view Centrify’s privacy policy.
For your convenience the Virginia Lottery website may provide links to other sites, including our own. However, the Virginia Lottery is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any websites to which we link that are not ours. When you click a link to visit another site, you are no longer on the Virginia Lottery Vendor Portal, and this Privacy Statement will no longer apply. At that point, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. If you have questions or concerns about a site to which we link, please read the privacy and security information for that site.
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
Cookies
Cookies and Technologies used by the Virginia Lottery
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies on this website.
Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate our site while persistent cookies enable us to track the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.
Session cookies expire when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.
You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site may be limited.
As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.
This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.
Contact Information
To offer comments about the Virginia Lottery Vendor Portal or to ask about the information presented in this Privacy Statement, please email us at vendorservices@valottery.com.
Our headquarters location and mailing address is: 600 E. Main Street, Richmond, VA 23219.
Effective February 7, 2019
×
Sign up for alerts
Customize your alerts by adding the ones most relevant to your gameplay below.
You'll need to first sign up for a MyGameRoom account.
If you have purchased a Subscription or entered a Lottery promotion in the past year, you are already a member and may login.
Register
Login
